A Guide to the Henry G. Kunkel papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA273
Rockefeller Archive Center
Henry G. Kunkel papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
1897, 1934-1987
bulk
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Rockefeller University
FA273
56.5 Cubic Feet 119 Boxes
File Plan
Former Classification: I 450 K964
Arrangement
This collection consists of 9 series based on the content or media of the collection. Some series were also further arranged into individual sub-series.
Series 1: Biographical Series 2: Correspondence Series 3: Notes and Notebooks Series 4: Professional Activities Sub-series: Advances in Immunology Sub-series: Conferences, Workshops, and Symposia Sub-series: Journal of Experimental Medicine Sub-series: Lectures and Manuscripts Series 5: Rockefeller University Sub-series: Correspondence Sub-series: General Sub-series: Personnel Series 6: Subject Files Series 7: Visual Materials Sub-series: Prints Sub-series: Negatives Sub-series: Slides Series 8: Reprints Sub-series: Kunkel and Associates Sub-series: Annotated Reprints by Others Series 9: Ephemera
Biographical / Historical
Henry G. Kunkel (1916-1983) was an immunologist and clinical investigator who was one of the earliest practitioners in the field of clinical immunology. He spent the majority of his career at The Rockefeller University (formerly the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research), beginning there as an Assistant Professor in 1945. In the early part of his career, he focused on basic immunology, using myeloma proteins to decipher the chain structure of immunoglobulins and antibodies. This work allowed for the first mapping of immunoglobulin genes to their respective chromosomes and the classification of antibodies.
In the latter part of his career, Dr. Kunkel focused primarily on the clinical investigation end of immunology. This included making significant strides in the studies of diseases such as systemic lupus erythematosus, rheumatoid arthritis, and chronic liver disease, as well as lymphoproliferative diseases (production of excessive quantities of lymphocytes) and primary immunodeficiency disorders (where parts of the body’s immune system are missing or not functioning properly). He was also an editor of the Journal of Experimental Medicine from 1960 until his death, and a co-founding editor of Advances in Immunology. Dr. Kunkel died on December 15, 1983.
September 9, 1916: Born in Brooklyn, New York to noted botanist Louis O. Kunkel (a member of the Rockefeller Institute) and horticulturist Joanna Kunkel. 1938-Graduated from Princeton University with a B.A. 1942-Graduated from Johns Hopkins University with an M.D. July 1942-March 1943-Intern at Bellevue Hospital March-August 1943-Assistant Resident at Bellevue Hospital August 1943-July 1946-Served in the Medical Corps of the U.S. Naval Research. Included active service in Italy. March 1945-December 1983-Appointed as a member of the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research in 1945, he later became a full member in 1952. Concurrently, he was also promoted from Assistant Resident Physician at The Rockefeller University Hospital to Physician. July 1950-June 1951-Visiting Investigator, Biochemical Institute (Uppsala, Sweden) 1973-1983-Adjunct Professor of Medicine at Cornell University Medical School (New York, New York) 1975-Received the Albert Lasker Basic Medical Research Award for contributions to the field of immunology, in particular to the understanding of how harmful imunologic responses can cause injury and disease, through his work with rheumatoid arthritis and kidney disease. 1976-1983-Abby Rockefeller Mauze Professor at The Rockefeller University 1977-Received the Louisa Gross Horwitz Prize for Biology or Biochemistry. It was awarded for his work in extending the study of immunology by creating the groundwork for a classification of immunoglobulins, as well as his work with rheumatoid arthritis and lupus erythematosus. December 15, 1983-Died in New York.
Separated Materials
Some items in this collection were separated into other collections at the Archive Center:
Photographs: Some photographs were removed before the collection was processed and incorporated into the Rockefeller University collection- RG1100 Photographs.
Books: These have been removed from the collection and added to the Rockefeller Archive Center library.
Instrument Catalogs: Added to the Rockefeller University collection-RG 851 Instrument and Equipment Catalogs.
Rockefeller University Publications: Consists of annual reports, News and Notes, and various other University-related publciations. These were removed and incorporporated into the appropriate collections.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for scholarly research with select materials restricted, as noted.
RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media and original digital media. In addition separated media may not yet have undergone stabilization procedures. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment.
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Related Materials
For the Louis O. Kunkel papers please see:
FA172 Louis O. Kunkel papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
- Biographical, 1943-1985; 1
  Arrangement
  Series 1: Biographical
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  Includes a bibliography of Dr. Kunkel as well as a number of biographical sources. Also includes: certificates, correspondence related to awards he received, administrative correspondence related to his appointments and promotions. There aer some photographs of both Dr. Kunkel and his laboratory at the Rockefeller University.
  Conditions Governing Access
  The collection is open for scholarly research with select materials restricted, as noted.
  RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media and original digital media. In addition separated media may not yet have undergone stabilization procedures. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
  - Administrative Correspondence (RU File), 1945-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Administrative Correspondence (RU File), 1949, 1974-1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - [Award Presentation-Ges. f. Immunologie-Mains], November 11, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bibliography-C. Moberg Working Materials, January 1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Biographical Clippings, 1973-1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Biographical-Miscellaneous, 1948-1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Certificates, 1958-1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Certificates, 1970-1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Congratulations, 1975-1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Curriculum Vitae (C.V.) and Bibliography (RU File), 1957 & 1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1977 & 1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Family Tree, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Honorary Degree Announcement-Harvard Medical School, Fall 1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Journal of Experimental Medicine (JEM) Appreciation, May 1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Kunkel, Henry G., 1980 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Personnel File
  - Kunkel, L.O. [Louis Otto]-Biographical Memoirs, 1960-1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Lab Associates, 1947-1983 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Lasker Award (contains address and manuscript), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Modern Medicine-Award for Distinguished Achievement, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Photographs, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Photographs-Kunkel's Laboratories, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Photographs (RU File), 1943-1977 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Revisions-Biography and Bibliography, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Scandinavian Journal of Immunology-"Special Issue for Henry George Kunkel on the Occasion of his 60th Birthday", September 9, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Symposium on Modern Immunology in Honor of Henry Kunkel, May 8, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Correspondence, 2
  Series 2: Correspondence
  Contains both personal and professional correspondence, both typed and handwritten.
  Some files are closed because they contain professional appointments or patient information.
  - A, 1968-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - A, 1968-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1A)
    Closed - File is restricted from scholarly research.
  - A (Adinolfi-Amos), 1973-1976 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - [AIDS Research], 1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Alabama Lecture, September 29, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - [Albert and Mary Lasker Foundation], 1978-1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - [American Clinical and Climatological Association], 1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Applications I, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Applications II, 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Applications III, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - [Asthma and Allergy Foundation of America], 1983 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - [Ba-Bh], 1967-1983 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - [Ba-Bh], 1967-1983 (Box 2, Folder 11A)
  - [Bi-Bu], 1964-1983 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - [Bi-Bu], 1964-1983 (Box 2, Folder 12A)
  - B (Baker-Brandeis), 1973-1982 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bonagura, Dr. Vincent R., 1977-1981 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Bronk, Detlev W., M.D., 1965-1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bunim Lecture-March 1, 1981, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - C (Capra-Cossman), 1961, 1973-1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - C, 1966-1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - C, 1966-1983 (Box 3, Folder 4A)
  - [California State Lupus Research Funds], 1982 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Cancelled Trip to Seattle-September 1982, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Capra, Dr. Donald, 1974-1983 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - [Carrel, S.- "Human Lymphocyte Subpopulations Detected by anti-Daudi Sera"], 1978 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Chiorazzi, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Clinical Aspects of Immunology-Chapter 1: "The Immunoglobulins", 1978-1981 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Coons Lecture-April 27, 1982, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - [Correspondence about Patients], A, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - [Correspondence about Patients], B, 1962-1969 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - [Correspondence about Patients], C, 1962-1969 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - [Correspondence about Patients], D, 1962-1972 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - [Correspondence about Patients], E, 1962-1966 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - [Correspondence about Patients], F, 1962-1969 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - [Correspondence about Patients], G, 1962-1970 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - [Correspondence about Patients], H, 1962-1970 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - [Correspondence about Patients], I-J, 1962-1969 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - [Correspondence about Patients], K, 1962-1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - [Correspondence about Patients], L, 1962-1967 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - [Correspondence about Patients], M, 1961-1970 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - [Correspondence about Patients], N, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - [Correspondence about Patients], O, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - [Correspondence about Patients], P, 1964-1971 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - [Correspondence about Patients], R, 1962-1969 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - [Correspondence about Patients], S, 1961-1970 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - [Correspondence about Patients], T, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - [Correspondence about Patients], U-V, 1963-1971 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - [Correspondence about Patients], W, 1962-1969 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - [Correspondence about Patients], X-Z, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence with Publishers, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - D, 1959-1983 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - D, 1959-1983 (Box 4, Folder 14A)
  - D (Deicher-Douglas), 1973-1982 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Dallas [Tribute to Morris Ziff], 1981 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - [Department of Health and Human Services], 1983 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Dr. Durant of Assoc. at Temple University, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - E, 1967-1983 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - E, 1967-1983 (Box 4, Folder 19A)
  - E (Ebers-Erlik), 1973-1978 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Eckhard [Kownataki], 1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Evelyn Hess- Chicago-[ARA Committee on Development of Programs with Industry], 1981-1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - F, 1960-1983 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - F, 1960-1983 (Box 5, Folder 4A)
  - F (Fauci-Fudenberg), 1970-1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - [Feizi, T.], 1973 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - G (Gatti-Grundy), 1961-1983 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - [Ga-Ge], 1971-1982 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - [Gi-Gu], 1966-1983 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - [Gi-Gu], 1966-1983 (Box 5, Folder 9A)
  - [The Gairdner Foundation], 1976-1983 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - [Galili, Uri], 1980 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - German, 1969-1973 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - German, 1969-1973 (Box 5, Folder 12A)
  - [Grubb, Anders], 1973 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - [Grubb, Anders], 1983 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - H, 1968-1983 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - H (Hamashima-Hümpel), 1973-1982 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Harry Winston Foundation, Inc., 1979-1982 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Harvard Degree, October 14-15, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Hepatic Cirrhosis, 1959-1970 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Hopkins, September 13, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Hughes Meeting, November 8-10, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - I (Immunochemistry-Ishizaka), 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - I, 1973-1980 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - I, 1973-1980 (Box 6, Folder 7A)
  - ICP [International Institute of Cellular and Molecular Pathology]-Brussels-June 12-13, 1980, 1979-1982 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - [Immunology], 1961 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - [Immunology], 1962, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - INSERM [Institut National de la Santé et de la Recherche Médicale] Conference-Paris, October 1-4, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Interesting Cases, 1959-1963 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Israel Visit, May 14-15, 1975, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - J, 1968-1983 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - J, 1968-1983 (Box 6, Folder 14A)
  - (Jacobs-Journal of Laboratory and Clinical Medicine), 1973-1980 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Janyce/Michele Deane, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Japan Conference, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - JMCI [The Journal of Molecular and Cellular Immunology], 1983 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - [The Johns Hopkins University Immunology Council], 1983 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - K (Kagey-Sobotka-Kronvall), 1967-1983 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - K, 1970-1983 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - K, 1970-1983 (Box 6, Folder 21A)
  - [Karolinska Institute], 1978-1984 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - L (Landaburu-Lupus Foundation of America), 1974-1982 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - L, 1964-1983 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - L, 1964-1983 (Box 7, Folder 2A)
  - LaFond, Richard E., 1981-1983 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Lahita Book, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Lahita, Robert G., 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - [Laurell, Dr. Carl-Bertil], 1973 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Lecture at Downstate [Medical Center], March 23, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - [Lefranc, Gérard], 1980 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Letters, 1963-1971 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Levine, Philip, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - [The Lita Annenberg] Hazen Award, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - [Loose Correspondence: Gregg-Mike], 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Ludwig Institute Review-Lausanne, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Lupus [Research] Institute-Gotthelf, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - M (Mage-Müller-Eberhard), 1974-1983 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - M, 1966-1983 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - M, 1966-1983 (Box 7, Folder 16A)
  - Maclyn McCarty, MD, 1971-1979 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - McCune, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - [Dr. Walsh McDermott], 1977 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Macy Foundation-Dr. Bowers, 1975-1978 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - [Manuscripts], 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Menarini Symposium-Florence, July 14-16, 1980, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - [Misc. Antigen/Immunology Correspondence], 1966-1969 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - [Misc. Foundations: Adolf Rosenberg Foundation-Sloan Kettering Institute for Cancer Research], 1978-1983 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - [Miscellaneous Personal Correspondence], 1976, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Montpellier-[International Symposium on New Trends in Human Immunology and Cancer Immunotherapy], 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - N (Natvig-Nurse), 1972-1981 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - N, 1976-1983 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - [National Academy of Sciences], 1980-1982 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - [National Science Foundation], 1976-1983 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Natvig, Jacob B., 1968-1977 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - [The New York Hospital and Cornell Medical Center], 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - [Nisonoff, Alfred], 1974 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Non Essential Mail, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - O (Odishaw-Ovary), 1959-1980 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - O, 1960-1983 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - O, 1960-1983 (Box 8, Folder 19A)
  - Odd and Miscellaneous Letters, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Outside Letters, etc.-Unrelated to Current Work, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Outside Letters, etc.-Unrelated to Current Work, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 21A)
  - P, 1964-1983 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - P, 1964-1983 (Box 9, Folder 1A)
  - P (Page-Putnam), 1973-1983 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - [The Passano Foundation, Inc.], 1976-1983 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Pasteur Medal, October 7, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - [Position Recommendations], 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Positions Available [Folder 1 of 3], 1963-1974 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Positions Available [Folder 2 of 3], 1974-1980 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Positions Available [Folder 3 of 3], 1979-1983 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - [Publication Correspondence], 1983 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Q, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Quie, Paul, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - [Quinn, Joseph R. -National Institutes of Health], 1977 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - R, 1966-1983 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - R, 1966-1983 (Box 9, Folder 13A)
  - R (Reeves-Rowe), 1970-1982 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - R (Reeves-Rowe), 1970-1982 (Box 9, Folder 14A)
  - [Rahmsdorf, H.J.], 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Rai-Long Island Jewish Talk, October 22, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Reeves, Westley H., 1980-1982 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - [Roche Institute of Molecular Biology], 1979-1980, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Roubinian, Jirayr, 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - The Royal Swedish Academy of Science-Foreign Member, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - [Sa-SLE], 1961-1983 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - [Sa-SLE], 1961-1983 (Box 10, Folder 5A)
  - [Sm-Sv], 1965-1983 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - [Sm-Sv], 1965-1983 (Box 10, Folder 6A)
  - S (Schrohenloher-Svejgaard), 1973-1983 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - [Schmid, Karl], 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Schrohenloher, Ralph E., 1963-1974 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Schwartz Paper-PNAS (Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences), 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - [Scripps Clinic and Research Foundation], 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Second Human B Cell Workshop-Bethesda, September 18-20, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Dr. Seitz, President-RU, 1968-1978 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Dr. Seitz, President-RU, 1968-1978 (Box 10, Folder 13A)
  - Seligmann, M., 1970-1975 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - [Seligmann, M.], 1973 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - [Serum Testing], 1959, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Shacknai Memorial Prize Lectureship-Jerusalem-December 1, 1980, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - SLE (Systemic Lupus Erythematosus] Meeting-October 2-3, 1980, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - [Steward, Bill], 1983 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - T, 1960-1983 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - T, 1960-1983 (Box 11, Folder 1A)
  - T (Tan-Trucco), 1970-1982 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Tan-Connors, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - [Turkewitz], 1983 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - U, 1963-1974 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - [The University of Alabama in Birmingham], 1983 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - V, 1967-1983 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - V (Vandvik-Vivona), 1970-1975 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Vande Stouwe, Robert, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Van Loghem, Erna and J., 1967-1971 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Van Loghem, Erna and J., 1967-1971 (Box 11, Folder 10A)
  - Vaughn, J.H., 1963-1983 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Vaughn, J.H., 1963-1983 (Box 11, Folder 11A)
  - W, 1958-1983 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - W (Waldmann-Winfield), 1968-1982 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - [Wally], 1979 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Williams, Ralph C., 1964-1967 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Winfield, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - X, Y,Z [Also included: Williams, Hibbard], 1961-1983 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Y,Z (Yount-Zucker), 1969-1982 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - [Yale University], 1982 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Unidentified Letters, 1981-1982 (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Notes and Notebooks, 1949-1984; 3
  Series 3: Notes and Notebooks
  Contains bound notebooks and loose notes written by Dr. Kunkel and his laboratory staff at the Rockefeller University. Subjects include: hemoglobins, immunofluorescence, lymphocytes, and monoclonal antibodies. There are also a number of notebooks that are listed solely by numbers or which are untitled. Some files are closed because they contain files of a sensitive nature, primarily identifiable patient information.
  - ACC CMC Work-R. Vande Stouwe Experiments, 3/20/74-1/14/75 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - A. Corning, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Ac-reactor, F. Becher system (anti-bovine)-Book #25, October 22, 1970-February 9, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - ANA Book I-C. Delaney, May 1977-January 1980 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Ancient Myeloma List (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - A. Singer-Experiments #1, July-September 1974 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Assorted Significant Older Data on Myeloma Proteins, 1970 and Undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Bemis-Woods-Mercapto-Early Allotypes Intermeds.-Book 14, April 25, 1959-June 23, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Book I-A5 to A44, 6/5-12/1/64 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Book #6-A203 to A349, 3/7-6/2/66 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Book #7 A350 to A397, 6/17/66-11/18/66 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Book #8-A398 to A435, November 28, 1966-January 11, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Book #9-A436 to A475, January 19-April 16, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Book #10-A476 to A553 [folder 1 of 2], April 6-September 14, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Book #10-A476 to A553 [folder 2 of 2], April 6-September 14, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Book #11-A554 to A620 [folder 1 of 2], September 18-December 27, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Book #11-A554 to A620 [folder 2 of 2], September 18-December 27, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Book #12-A621 to A671 [folder 1 of 2], January 3-April 2, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Book #12-A621 to A671 [folder 2 of 2], January 3-April 2, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Book #13-A672 to A724 [folder 1 of 2], April 3-August 30, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Book #13-A672 to A724 [folder 2 of 2], April 3-August 30, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Book #14-A725 to A795 [folder 1 of 2], September 9, 1968-January 8, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Book #14-A725 to A795 [folder 2 of 2], September 9, 1968-January 8, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Book #15-A796 to A884 [folder 1 of 2], January 14-June 19, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Book #15-A796 to A884 [folder 2 of 2], January 14-June 19, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Book #16-A885 to A975 [folder 1 of 2], June 25-December 8, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Book # 16-A885 to A975 [folder 2 of 2], June 25-December 8, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Book #17-A976 to A1076 [folder 1 of 2], December 9, 1969-May 14, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Book #17-A 976 to A1076 [folder 2 of 2], December 9, 1969-May 14, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Book #18-A1077 to A1158 [folder 1 of 2], May 15-December 28, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Book #18- A1077 to A1158 [folder 2 of 2], May 15-December 28, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Book #19-A1159 to A1229 [folder 1 of 2], January 12-May 5, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Book #19- A1159 to A1229 [folder 2 of 2], January 12-May 5, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Book #20-A1230 to A1350 [folder 1 of 2], May 17, 1971-July 16, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Book #20-A1230 to A1350 [folder 2 of 2], May 17, 1971- July 16, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 5)